

# **Mehmet Deveci**

# Senior Frontend Developer/Full Stack Developer

I have been working with Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, TypeScript, Next.js, PHP and Node.js, with a focus on crafting seamless user experiences, applications and infrastructures in the last 5 years in Berlin.

deveci2024@gmail.com

Berlin, Germany

+49 (178) 8980493

LinkedIn

https://www.volcode.org/

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Sdui GmbH Berlin, Germany

# Senior Frontend Developer

February 2023 - July 2024

- Developed an event management system, boosted user interaction at least 20% through new editing features.
- Conceptualized and implemented video conference features for an app, improved user engagement with React.
- Wrote technical documentation that streamlined onboarding, reducing setup time by 30% on WebSockets.
- Guided junior developers through pair programming, enhancing their front-end skills and productivity.
- Developed a migration guide to help developers transition from Vue 2 to Vue 3 efficiently.
   See More

Homeday GmbH Berlin, Germany

Senior Frontend Developer

March 2020 - January 2023

- Migrated components and pages from PHP to Vue + Nuxt, improved page speeds up to 30%.\*use case
- Built Infrastructure as Code with AWS and GitHub Actions at Homeday, reducing costs by 15%.\*use case
- Optimized CI/CD pipelines by using Jest, Cypress, Vue Util Tests, and replacing unit tests with integration tests, reducing pipeline lifetime by 25%.
- Built, optimized, improved and maintained multiple apps with HTML5, CSS3, Javascript & Typescript, Vue, using BEM CSS, Storybook, Design System, NPM with a team of 30+ people in engineering.
- Mentored junior developers, enabling promotions within 8 months.
   See More

### **Turkish Radio Television Corporation**

Istanbul, Turkey

Frontend Developer

March 2018 - March 2020

- Optimized election result pages, reducing load times by 25% for high volume of users during peak traffic.
- Built an embedded SVG-based map with Vue.js for Turkey's 2018 General Elections, handling 75k+ concurrent
  users with 100% uptime.
- Redesigned the internal image database, reducing search times by 50% and boosting editor efficiency.
- Developed and optimized a CMS editor, streamlining content creation for editors across the media platform.

### **Crabs Media - A Digital Web Agency**

Istanbul, Turkey

Frontend Developer

May 2013 - May 2017

• Built 50+ interfaces with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, and SQL (WordPress) for clients in diverse industries.

# **Fatih Municipality**

Istanbul, Turkey

IT Support Internship

May 2012 - September 2012

# **SKILLS**

Vue, Nuxt.js, TypeScript, React, Next.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Nest.js, WebSockets, PHP, Vite, Figma, Contentful, Stakeholder Management, Rest API, AWS, Cypress, Jest, Webpack, Git, Github, Docker, Postman, HTML, CSS, SCSS, LESS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Figma, Agile, Scrum, Kanban, BEM, MySQL, Laravel, Symfony, SQL, UI / UX

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Istanbul Arel University**

Istanbul, Turkey

Associate's Degree on Computer Programming

2017

# **Inonu Technical High School**

Istanbul, Turkey

Vocational Training on Information Technologies

2013

### **CERTIFICATES**

Communicating with Emotional Intelligence, Interpersonal Communication, Writing a Tech Resume

# **DIVERSITY & INCLUSION**

During my time at Homeday, I co-led a Diversity and Inclusion Taskforce, where I gained valuable experience in fostering inclusivity and collaboration within the workplace;

- Designed and implemented team-building strategies and OKRs.
- Delivered impactful Unconscious Bias Training, fostering awareness across teams.
- Planned and facilitated workshops, promoting inclusive and collaborative work culture.

### **LINKS**

- \* View recommendations from colleagues and managers on my LinkedIn profile.
- \* Check my github profile I OR my github profile II to observe some of my open source projects
- \* Watch my introduction video in 2m